

COLLEGE PARK MD, USA

🛮 +1 2408257455 | 🔀 bansal01@umd.edu | 🄏 arpitbansal297.github.io | 🖸 github.com/arpitbansal297

Research Interests_

My research primarily revolves around the empirical analysis and optimization of Deep Neural Network architectures with the aim of improving their training and inference mechanisms. I am particularly interested in a range of vision tasks, including text-to-image generation, image editing, and image reasoning. My work in these areas incorporates both diffusion and autoregressive methods to address various challenges in image processing. Additionally, I have investigated algorithmic synthesis via neural networks to enable logical reasoning and developed robust watermarking techniques to maintain the security and integrity of neural network models.

Education

University of Maryland, College Park

College Park Jan 2021 - present

PHD CANDIDATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (3.925/4.0)

• Advisor: Prof. Tom Goldstein

• Dean's Fellowship

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

Kharagpur, India Aug 2014 - May 2019

BACHELORS + MASTERS IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

• Minor in Computer Science

· Advisor: Prof. Rajiv Ranjan Sahay

Industry Experience ____

Meta	Gen	ΔΙ	(ш	lama	h

May 2024 -

AI Research Scientist Intern

Present

In collaboration with the Llama team, developing multi-modal Generative Models with a focus on image reasoning and multi-turn image editing in any-to-any models.

Amazon AWS AI labs

June 2023 -

Applied Science Intern

Aug 2023

Examined the challenges of existing Text-to-Image Diffusion models' low fidelity and devised a novel approach to produce high-fidelity images conditioned on text.

Visa Incorporated, India

July 2019 -Dec 2020 Software Developer

Designed an NLP engine for intuitive English queries and an impactful Recommendation System, earning a Visa Trade Secret. Introduced a Merchant Rating system based on transaction nature, recognized with another Trade Secret for its Research and Development.

Visa Incorporated, India

May 2018 -July 2018 Software Developer Intern

Developed a robust algorithm to discern relationships among thousands of database columns by analyzing their English-named titles and the frequency of their combined queries.

Selected Publications

Cold diffusion: Inverting arbitrary image transforms without noise

A. Bansal, E. Borgnia, H. Chu, J Li, H. Kazemi, F. Huang, M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, T. Goldstein *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (Neurips)* 2023

Universal guidance for diffusion models

A. Bansal*, H. Chu*, A. Schwarzschild, S. Sengupta, M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2024*

End-to-end Algorithm Synthesis with Recurrent Networks: Logical Extrapolation Without Overthinking

A. Bansal*, A. Schwarzchild*, E. Borgnia, Z. Emam, F. Huang, M. Goldblum, T. Goldstein *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (Neurips) 2022*

Certified Neural Network Watermarks with Randomized Smoothing

A. Bansal*, P. Yeh Chiang*, M. Curry, R. Jain, C. Wigington, V. Manjunatha, J. P Dickerson, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML - Spotlight) 2022*

Can You Learn the Same Model Twice? Investigating Reproducibility and Double Descent from the Decision Boundary Perspective

G. Somepalli, L. Fowl, **A. Bansal**, P. Yeh Chiang, Y. Dar, R. Baraniuk, M.GoldBlum, T. Goldstein *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR - Oral) 2022*

Transfer Learning with Deep Tabular Models

R. Levin*, V. Cherepanova*, A. Schwarzschild†, **A. Bansal**†, C Bayan Bruss, T. Goldstein, A. G. Wilson, M. Goldblum *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2023*

Canary in a Coalmine: Better Membership Inference with Ensembled Adversarial Queries

Y. Wen, **A. Bansal**, H. Kazemi, E. Borgnia, M. Goldblum, J. Geiping, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR - Spotlight) 2023*

Gradient-based optimization is not necessary for generalization in neural networks

P. Yeh Chiang, R. Ni, D. Yu Miller, **A. Bansal**, J. Geiping, M. Goldblum, T. Goldstein *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR - Spotlight)* 2023

1000	hina	LVDARIADAA
1040	111110	
1 Cuc	5	Experience

Fall 2021 **Control Systems**, Teaching Assistant Spring 2021 **Operating Systems**, Teaching Assistant

University of Maryland, College Park University of Maryland, College Park

Relevant Course-work __

Machine Learning Information Retrieval (IIT), Machine Learning (IIT), Speech and NLP (IIT), Deep Learning

(UMD), Algorithms in Machine Learning (UMD)

Signal Processing Digital Signal Processing (IIT), Statistical Signal Processing (IIT), Probability and Stochastic

Processes (IIT), Random Processes (UMD), Information Theory (UMD), Numerical Analysis I

(UMD), Advanced Numerical Optimization (UMD)